Robert Rocco Basso

(978) 504-1244 ■ robertbasso2@gmail.com ■ 20 Bay Street, Amesbury MA, 01913

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with experience designing scalable and resilient backends via indexing, eager loading, multi-level data validation, database normalization/denormalization, and cacheing; and responsive frontends with media queries, SCSS variables and mixins, and AJAX requests.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, ReactJS, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Java, Eclipse, C#, SQL, PostgreSQL, ActiveRecord, Heroku, Git, Github, Foundation, Bootstrap, RSpec, Capybara, MiniTest, Puma, AWS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DollarshipSoftware Engineer

Boston, MA

May 2017 - Aug. 2017

Core API

- Created objects all with database and model level data validation, indexes, both singular & compound, when speed or uniqueness was required, and polymorphic classes where necessary
- Implemented CRUD functionality around data models often involving custom SQL and database joins
- Wrote unit tests to ensure all code was high quality and sustainable
- Developed scoped controllers to guarantee only verified users/admin could access proprietary data

Admin Console

- Designed ReactJS components for admin to export sweepstakes data into a CSV, add mail in users, and add spending thresholds for bonus credits
- Utilized PropTypes validations to alert future developers and users if required data was missing

Cannonball Email

Boston, MA

Software Engineer

Sept. 2015 – Mar. 2017

MyBlendApp

- Designed responsive front end that retained the user interface on screen sizes ranging from smart phones to computer displays
- Incorporated features such as AJAX requests for "Up Next" content, infinite scrolling functionality, filtering by keywords or topic, and displaying of personal emails for registered users

Customer Relationship Manager

- Implemented caching mechanism to store the IDs of articles recommended for a particular user to mitigate loading time
- Employed database denormalization to minimize response times

PROJECTS

Park Easy

- Implemented custom JavaScript and jQuery to give users several methods to add parking areas to the map, open index menus, etc.
- Integrated with Google, Facebook, and Twitter OAuth to give users multiple login options

ShowUp

- Integrated with Spotify API to provide song previews and album artwork for each concert listing
- Utilized ActiveRecord eager loading to improve rendering time of the index page

EDUCATION Boston, MA

Northeastern University

Sept. 2009 - June 2014

B S Mathematics

Minor Computer Science